Guide to the Clifton R. Merritt Papers 1935-2008
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- The Wilderness Society, 1954-2000; Series III; 23.75 linear feet
  - Subject Files, 1954-1989; Subseries 2; 22.70 linear feet
    - Deerlodge National Forest-General Phase II, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Deerlodge National Forest-General Phase III, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Deerlodge National Forest-North End, 1976 (Box-folder 15/15)
    - Dolores River Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Dolores River-Proposed Wild and Scenic, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Dolores River-Wild and Scenic River Study-Public Meetings Notes, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Eagle's Nest Wilderness, 1964-1975 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Ecological Impact of Outfitting in Montana, 1974 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Elkhorn Environmental Impact Statement, Maps, and Proposals, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Elkhorn Wilderness, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Elkhorn Wilderness, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 16/8)
    - Elkhorn Wilderness, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 16/9)
    - Elkhorn Wilderness Area-Helena National Forest, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 16/10-11)
    - Elkhorn Wilderness Proposed Wilderness Study Area Clippings-Helena and Deerlodge National Forest, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Endangered American Wilderness Act-Colorado Areas, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 17/2)
    - Environmental Statements-Colorado Parks, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 17/3-4)
    - Flat Tops Primitive Area-Colorado, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 17/5-6)
    - Flat Tops Wilderness, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 17/7)
    - Flat Tops Wilderness-Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 17/8-10)
    - Flat Tops Wilderness-Statements and Mailers, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 18/1-4)
    - Flathead Clippings-North, South, and Middle Forks, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Flathead National Forest, 1954-1970 (Box-folder 18/6)
    - Flathead National Forest-General Phase I, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 18/7-9)
    - Flathead National Forest-General Phase II, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Flathead National Forest-General Phase III, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 19/2-3)
    - Flathead National Forest-Middle Fork-Continental Divide Wilderness Study Area, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 19/4-5)
    - Flathead National Forest-Mission Mountain Wilderness, 1963-1974 (Box-folder 19/6-8)
    - Flathead National Forest-Mission Mountain Wilderness, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 20/1-2)
    - Flathead National Forest-Roadless Area Review, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 20/3)
    - Flathead-Continental Divide Wilderness Study Area-Flathead and Lewis and Clark National Forests, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 20/4-5)
    - Dave Foreman, Historical Overview of the Wilderness Society, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 20/6)
    - Forest Service comments on the Montana Wilderness Act of 1975, S. 393, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 20/7)
    - Fort Hawley Game Preserve, 1963 (Box-folder 20/8)
    - Fort Hawley Waterfowl Development, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 20/9-11)
    - Fox Creek Area, Gallatin National Forest, 1977 (Box-folder 20/12)
    - Friends of the Dolores, 1978 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Gallatin National Forest-Absaroka-Beartooth Primitive Area, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Gallatin National Forest-General Phase I, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 21/3)
    - Gallatin National Forest-General Phase II, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Gallatin National Forest-General Phase III, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Gallatin National Forest-Lionhead, undated (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Gallatin River-Proposed Wild and Scenic River, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Gallatin, Beaverhead National Forests-Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Taylor Hilgard-Legislation and Clippings, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 21/8)
    - Glacier National Park, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 22/1-3)
    - Glacier National Park, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 22/4)
    - Glacier Park Wilderness-Mailer and Memo, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 22/5)
    - Grasslands Articles, 1967 (Box-folder 22/6)
    - Grave Creek-Eureka-Kootenai National Forest, 1974 (Box-folder 22/7)
    - Great Bear Wilderness #1, 1977 (Box-folder 22/8)
    - Great Bear Wilderness #2, 1978 (Box-folder 22/9)
    - Great Bear Wilderness #3, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 22/10)
    - Grizzly Bear Recovery, 1966 (Box-folder 23/1)
    - Hearing Statements, S. 393, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 23/2)
    - Helena City Park-Montana, 1975 (Box-folder 23/3)
    - Helena National Forest-Gates of the Mountain Wilderness, 1965-1978 (Box-folder 23/4)
    - Helena National Forest-General Phase I, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 23/5)
    - Helena National Forest-General Phase II, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 23/6)
    - Helena National Forest-General Phase III, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 23/7-8)
    - Helena National Forest-Mount Baldy Roadless Area, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 23/9)
    - Hells Canyon National Recreation Area, 1964-1970 (Box-folder 23/10)
    - Hells Canyon National Recreation Area, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 23/11-12)
    - Hells Canyon National Recreation Area, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 24/1-2)
    - Hells Canyon National Recreation Area, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 24/3-5)
    - Hells Canyon National Recreation Area, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 24/6)
    - Hells Canyon National Recreation Area, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 25/1-4)
    - Hells Canyon National Recreation Area, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 25/5)
    - HR 39-Alaksa National Interest Lands Conservation Act-Clippings, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 25/6-7)
    - HR 39-Alaksa National Interest Lands Conservation Act Counter and Related Proposals, 1977 (Box-folder 26/1)
    - HR 39-Alaksa National Interest Lands Conservation ActD-2 Pronunciation Sheet, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 26/2)
    - HR 39-Alaksa National Interest Lands Conservation Act General, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 26/3-4)
    - HR 39-Alaksa National Interest Lands Conservation Act General Legislation, 1978 (Box-folder 26/5)
    - HR 39-Alaksa National Interest Lands Conservation Act Hearing Statements, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 26/6)
    - HR 39-Alaksa National Interest Lands Conservation Act Hearing Statements, 1977 (Box-folder 26/7)
    - HR 39-Alaksa National Interest Lands Conservation Act Interior Committee Cosponsors, 1977 (Box-folder 26/8)
    - HR 39-Alaksa National Interest Lands Conservation Act Interior Department Comments, 1977 (Box-folder 26/9)
    - Humbug Spires Primitive Area-Dillon Bureau of Land Management, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 26/10)
    - Hyalite-Porcupine-Buffalo Horn Proposed Wilderness Study Area, Gallatin National Forest, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 27/1-3)
    - Information from the Forest Service on 9 of the 9 Areas in the Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1975, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 27/4)
    - International Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies Meeting, Clifton Merritt Speech regarding Fish and Wildlife Management, 1978 (Box-folder 27/5)
    - Jewel Basin Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Flathead National Forest, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 27/6)
    - Kootenai National Forest-Big Swede Pipe Land Use Planning, 1976 (Box-folder 27/7)
    - Kootenai National Forest-General Phase I, 1972 (Box-folder 27/8)
    - Kootenai National Forest-General Phase II, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 27/9)
    - Kootenai National Forest-General Phase III, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 27/10-13)
    - Kootenai National Forest-Maps, 1977 (Box-folder 28/1)
    - Kootenai National Forest-O'Brien, Seventeen mile, Cross Mountain Land Use Planning, 1976 (Box-folder 28/2)
    - Kootenai National Forest-Ziegler Land Use Planning, 1976 (Box-folder 28/3)
    - Lee Metcalf Wilderness-Clyde Park-Dillon Transmission Line, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 28/4)
    - Legislation Needed to Save the Upper Selway, 1966 (Box-folder 28/5)
    - Letter Regarding S. 393 to Montana CWs and Members, 1975 (Box-folder 28/6)
    - Lewis and Clark National Forest-Big Snowies Proposed Wilderness Study Area, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 28/7)
    - Lewis and Clark National Forest-Middle Fork Judith Proposed Wilderness Study Area, 1967-1978 (Box-folder 28/8-9)
    - Lewis and Clark national Forest-Rocky Mountain Front and Continental Divide Wilderness Study Areas, 1971 (Box-folder 28/10)
    - Lewis and Clark National Forest-Tenderfoot-Deep Creek Roadless Areas, 1978 (Box-folder 28/11)
    - Lincoln Back Country, 1963-1976 (Box-folder 28/12)
    - Lincoln Back Country, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 28/13)
    - Lincoln Back Country, 1967 (Box-folder 28/14)
    - Lincoln Back Country-Scapegoat Wilderness Proposal, 1964-1972 (Box-folder 29/1-3)
    - Lincoln Scapegoat, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 29/4)
    - Lincoln-Scapegoat, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 29/5)
    - Lincoln Scapegoat, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 29/6)
    - Lincoln Scapegoat, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 29/7)
    - Lincoln-Scapegoat, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 30/1)
    - Lincoln-Scapegoat, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 30/2-3)
    - Lincoln-Scapegoat, 1969 (Box-folder 30/4-5)
    - Lincoln-Scapegoat Wilderness, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 30/6)
    - Lincoln-Scapegoat-Correspondence, Notes and Clippings, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 30/7-8)
    - Lolo National Forest-Big Hole, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 30/9)
    - Lolo National Forest-Rattlesnake Roadless Area Proposed Wilderness Study Area, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 31/1-2)
    - Lolo National Forest-Welcome Creek, 1977 (Box-folder 31/3)
    - Medicine Lake National Wildlife Refuge, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 31/4)
    - Metcalf and Mansfield Wilderness Bill, S.107, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31/5)
    - Lee Metcalf, 1967 (Box-folder 31/6)
    - Middle Fork of the Flathead-Correspondence and Articles, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 31/7-8)
    - Middle Fork of the Flathead-Correspondence and Articles, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 31/9)
    - Middle Fork-Continental Divide Wilderness Study Area-Great Bear, 1957-1978 (Box-folder 32/1-2)
    - Mission Mountain Tribal Wilderness, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 32/3)
    - Mission Mountains Wilderness-Flathead National Forest, 1963-1979 (Box-folder 32/4-6)
    - Missouri Breaks Proposed Scenic Recreation River, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 32/7)
    - Missouri Breaks Proposed Scenic Recreation River, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 32/8)
    - Missouri Breaks Proposed Wildlife Area, 1965-1975 (Box-folder 33/1)
    - Missouri River-Miscellaneous, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 33/2)
    - Montana Bureau of Land Management Wilderness Review, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 33/3)
    - Montana Conservation, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 33/4)
    - Montana Established Wilderness, 1978 (Box-folder 33/5)
    - Montana Fish and Wildlife, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 33/6)
    - Montana Forest Service Roadless Area Review, Phase II, 1979 (Box-folder 33/7)
    - Montana Highway Department-Gallatin National Forest, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 33/8)
    - Montana Lands, S. 393, 1979 (Box-folder 33/9)
    - Montana Missouri River Breaks Congressional Record Excerpts, S. 1506, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 33/10)
    - Montana National Parks, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 33/11)
    - Montana Natural Areas System, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 33/12)
    - Montana Rivers-North Fork of the Flathead-Cabin Creek, Canada Mine, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 33/13)
    - Montana Roadless Area Review I-Phase I, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 33/14)
    - Montana Roadless Area Review I-Phase II, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 34/1)
    - Montana Roadless Area Review I-Phase III, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 34/2)
    - Montana Roadless Area Review II-Phase I, 1977 (Box-folder 34/3)
    - Montana Roadless Area Review II-Phase II, 1978 (Box-folder 34/4)
    - Montana Roadless Area Review II-Phase III, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 34/5)
    - Montana Roadless Area Review II-Phase III, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 34/6)
    - Montana Stream Preservation Act, 1965-1975 (Box-folder 34/7)
    - Montana Wild and Scenic Rivers, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 34/8)
    - Montana Wilderness, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 34/9)
    - Montana Wilderness Bill, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 34/10)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Act, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 34/11-12)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Act Clippings, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 34/13)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1974 (Box-folder 35/1)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1974-Lee Metcalf, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 35/2-3)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1975, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 35/4-5)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1975-Correspondence (Box-folder 35/6-7)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1975-S. 393-Maps-Revised 1976 (Box-folder 35/8)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1977-Maps, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 35/9)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Act-Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 35/10-11)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Area Act of 1975, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 36/1-2)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Area-Maps, 1975 (Box-folder 36/3)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Bill 1977, S. 393-Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 36/4)
    - Montana Wilderness Study Bill 1977, S. 393-Legislation (Box-folder 36/5)
    - Montana, 1964 and Previous, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 36/6)
    - Mount Henry Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Kootenai National Forest, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 36/7)
    - National Bison Range, 1974 (Box-folder 36/8)
    - Northern Rockies Action Group, 1978 (Box-folder 36/9)
    - Northern Tier Pipeline, 1979 (Box-folder 36/10)
    - Pacific Northwest Conservation Council, 1968 (Box-folder 36/11)
    - Policy for Wilderness within National Forests-Rupert Cutler, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 37/1)
    - Powderhorn Primitive Area-Montrose District Office-Colorado Bureau of Land Management, 1972 (Box-folder 37/2)
    - Proposed Absaroka Beartooth Wilderness-Absaroka Beartooth Task Force, 1971 (Box-folder 37/3)
    - Proposed Beartooth Wilderness-Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 37/4)
    - Proposed Lincoln Backcountry Wilderness, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 37/5)
    - Proposed Sun Butte Dams, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 37/6-7)
    - Proposed Sun Butte Dams, 1965 (Box-folder 37/8-10)
    - Pryor Mountains Wild Horse Range, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 38/1)
    - Ravalli Waterfowl Refuge, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 38/2)
    - Red Rock Lakes National Wildlife Refuge, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 38/3-5)
    - Redwoods Bill, 1968 (Box-folder 38/6)
    - Reference Acts, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 38/7)
    - Reichle Dam-Big Hole River-Proposed Wild and Scenic River, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 38/8)
    - River of No Return-Idaho and Salmon River Breaks Primitive Areas-Wilderness Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 38/9-10)
    - Roadless Area Review I and Roadless Area Review II, Montana, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 39/1)
    - Roadless Area Review II, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 39/2-4)
    - Roadless Area Review II, 1978 (Box-folder 39/5)
    - Roadless Area Review II References, 1979 (Box-folder 39/6)
    - Rock Creek Proposed Wild and Scenic River, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 39/7)
    - Rocky Mountain Front Land Management Plan, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 39/8)
    - Russell Fiord Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Tongass National Forest, 1970 (Box-folder 39/9)
    - Sapphire Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Bitterroot and Deerlodge National Forests, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 39/10-11)
    - Sapphire Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Bitterroot and Deerlodge National Forests, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 40/1-2)
    - Sapphire Wilderness Study Area-Bitterroot National Forest-North Sapphire Area, 1977 (Box-folder 40/3)
    - Scapegoat Enlargement-Helena, Lolo, and Lewis and Clark National Forests Proposed Wilderness Study Areas, 1963-1977 (Box-folder 40/4)
    - Scapegoat Wilderness-Bills, 1965 (Box-folder 40/5)
    - Scapegoat Wilderness-Proposals, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 40/6)
    - Scapegoat Wilderness-Helena, Lolo, and Lewis and Clark National Forests, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 40/7-8)
    - Scenic and Wild Rivers-Yellowstone River-Montana, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 40/9)
    - Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness-Big Creek Dam, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 41/1)
    - Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness-Bitterroot, Lolo National Forests, 1965 (Box-folder 41/2)
    - Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness-Wilderness Society Trips, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 41/3)
    - Ski Yellowstone, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 41/4)
    - South San Juans #1, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 41/5)
    - South San Juans #2, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 41/6)
    - Spanish Peaks Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 41/7-8)
    - Spanish Peaks Correspondence, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 41/9)
    - Spanish Peaks Hearing Statements, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 41/10)
    - Spanish Peaks Primitive Area, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 42/1)
    - Spanish Peaks Primitive Area-Gallatin National Forest Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 42/2)
    - Spanish Peaks Primitive Area-Gallatin National Forest Correspondence, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 42/3-5)
    - Spanish Peaks Primitive Area-Gallatin National Forest Correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 42/6)
    - Spanish Peaks Primitive Area-Gallatin National Forest Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 42/7-8)
    - Spanish Peaks Primitive Area-Gallatin National Forest Maps, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 42/9-10)
    - Spanish Peaks Primitive Area-Jack Creek Area, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 43/1-5)
    - Spanish Peaks Wilderness, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 43/6-8)
    - Spanish Peaks Wilderness, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 44/1)
    - Spanish Peaks-Gallatin National Forest, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 44/2)
    - Spanish Peaks-Jack Creek, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 44/3)
    - St. Louis Peak Roadless Area, 1973 (Box-folder 44/4)
    - State Wilderness Waterways, 1966 (Box-folder 44/5)
    - Statement before Magruder Corridor Committee, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 44/6)
    - Summaries of D-2 Environmental Impact Statement, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 44/7)
    - Sun River Game Preserve-Bob Marshall Wilderness, 1964 (Box-folder 44/8)
    - Swan Bunker Wilderness Study Area-Flathead National Forest, 1964-1974 (Box-folder 44/9)
    - Sweetwater-Honker Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Tongass National Forest, 1975 (Box-folder 44/10)
    - Taylor-Hilgard-Montana Wilderness Study Area-Correspondence, 1958-1977 (Box-folder 45/1-3)
    - Taylor-Hilgard Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Gallatin and Beaverhead National Forests, Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 45/4-7)
    - Ten Lakes Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Kootenai National Forest, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 45/8)
    - Thompson Seton Wilderness Study Area-Flathead and Kootenai National Forests, 1975 (Box-folder 45/9)
    - Timber Practices, 1970 (Box-folder 45/10-11)
    - Timber Practices, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 46/1-3)
    - Timber Practices, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 46/4-5)
    - Tongass National Forest-Misty Fiords Proposed Wilderness Study Area, 1978 (Box-folder 46/6)
    - Tracy Arms Fiord Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Tongass National Forest, 1971 (Box-folder 46/7)
    - UL Bend National Wildlife Refuge, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 46/8)
    - United States Geological Survey Topographic Map of Montana, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 46/9)
    - Upper Selway #4-Magruder Corridor, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 47/1-3)
    - Upper Selway Proposed Forest Service Logging Area, undated (Box-folder 47/4)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness, 1964 (Box-folder 47/5)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness, 1965 (Box-folder 47/6-8)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness, 1965 (Box-folder 48/1-3)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 48/4)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness, 1966 (Box-folder 48/5)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness, 1966 (Box-folder 48/6-8)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 49/1)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness, 1970 (Box-folder 49/2-3)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness-Magruder Corridor Review, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 49/4-5)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness-Magruder Corridor Review #1, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 49/6-8)
    - Upper Selway Wilderness-Magruder Corridor Review #1, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 50/1-3)
    - Utah Wilderness Resources, 1977 (Box-folder 50/4)
    - War Horse Lake National Wildlife Refuge, 1973 (Box-folder 50/5)
    - Washington State Sportsmen's Council-North Cascades, circa 1970 (Box-folder 50/6)
    - Weminuche Wilderness-Colorado-San Juan National Forest, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 50/7)
    - West Big Hole Wilderness, 1973 (Box-folder 50/8)
    - West Chichagof-Yakobi Island Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Tongass National Forest, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 50/9-10)
    - Wild and Scenic Rivers Act, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 50/11)
    - Wild Missouri River-Montana #1, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 50/12)
    - Wild Missouri River-Montana #2, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 51/1-2)
    - Wild Missouri River-Montana #3, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 51/3-4)
    - Wild Missouri River-Montana #4, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 51/5)
    - Wild Missouri River-Montana #5, 1963-1978 (Box-folder 51/6-8)
    - Wild Missouri River-Montana Clippings, 1965-1976 (Box-folder 52/1)
    - Wild Missouri River-Montana Hearing Statements, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 52/2)
    - Wild Missouri River-Montana Legislation, 1965-1976 (Box-folder 52/3)
    - Wild River System, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 52/4)
    - Wild River-Middle Fork of the Flathead, 1965 (Box-folder 52/5)
    - Wild Rivers Bill System, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 52/6-7)
    - Wilderness Acts, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 52/8)
    - Wilderness Bills-Drafts, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 52/9)
    - Wilderness Classification Procedures, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 52/10)
    - Wilderness Clippings, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 52/11)
    - Wilderness Conventions, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 52/12)
    - Wilderness Preservation System-Clippings, Correspondence, Memos, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 52/13)
    - Wilderness Proposals, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 53/1)
    - Wilderness Resource Areas-New Mexico/West Texas, 1977 (Box-folder 53/2)
    - Wilderness Review-Department of the Interior, 1978 (Box-folder 53/3)
    - Wilderness System, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 53/4)
    - Wildlife Refuges, 1965 (Box-folder 53/5)
    - Wood Tikchik Area-Tongass National Forest, undated (Box-folder 53/6)
    - Yakutat Forelands Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Tongass National Forest, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 53/7)
    - Yellowstone National Park, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 53/8)
    - Yellowstone National Park-Big Sky Resort, 1975 (Box-folder 53/9)
    - Yellowstone River National Recreation Area, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 53/10)
- The American Wilderness Alliance / American Wildlands, 1957-2007; Series IV; 29.5 linear feet
  In 1979, Clif Merritt, Sally Ranney, and Jerry Mallet formed The American Wilderness Alliance (known after 1983 as American Wildlands) based in Denver, Colorado. The organization worked with conservation groups throughout the Rocky Mountain West to preserve public lands for wildlife habitat and recreation. Merritt served as executive director until 1990, when he became associate executive director. In 1990, Merritt began the Corridors of Life Program, which used Geographic Information Systems to map wildlife migration corridors between roadless areas and established wilderness areas.
  This series is arranged into four subseries. Subseries 1: Administration includes internal memos and correspondence, meeting notes and minutes, resumes, notes, and financial and funding information. Subseries 2: Subject Files consists of correspondence, notes, research files, action reports, and clippings. Of particular interest are Subseries 3: Corridors of Life contains correspondence, research files, and notes. Subseries 4: Organizational Publications and Newsletters contains newsletters and publications, correspondence, notes, and drafts.
  - Administration, 1965-2007; Subseries 1; 5 linear feet
    - 25th Anniversary Celebration, 2002 (Box-folder 53/11)
    - About American Wilderness Alliance, undated (Box-folder 53/12)
    - About American Wilderness Alliance, 1988 (Box-folder 53/13)
    - About American Wildlands, 1980-1996 (Box-folder 53/14)
    - Advisory Council, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 53/15)
    - Rob Ament, Executive Director, Correspondence, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 53/16)
    - Rob Ament, Resume, 1996 (Box-folder 53/17)
    - Annual Review, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 53/18)
    - Annual Review, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 53/19)
    - Arrow Corporation, Yvon Chouinard, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 53/20)
    - Arrow Corporation, Yvon Chouinard, 1987 (Box-folder 53/21)
    - Board and Advisors List, office and Field Staff List, 1993 and undated (Box-folder 53/22)